<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy | Mahesh Arumugam</title>
    <link>/tag/privacy/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Privacy</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Privacy</title>
      <link>/tag/privacy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signet-ring: A framework for authenticating sources and lineages of digital objects</title>
      <link>/project/signet-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/signet-ring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verifying sources of information is vital in assessing the credibility of facts
and data in our increasingly digital world; often, the verification of the sources
is as necessary as the information they provide. To battle misinformation and
disinformation through digital objects, it is salient to provide consumers the ability
to verify whether or not information (or data) provided by such sources was altered
prior to its use (e.g., publication). To address these concerns, we designed and implemented
Signet-ring. Signet-ring registers and authenticates all
participants in the origination and publication process, potentially including the sources,
publishers, and applications. It manages the following critical workflows: (1) documentation
and verification of the relationships between objects and sources (certification),
(2) documentation and verification of the relationships between different related objects
(lineage), and (3) authentication of sources to each other (handshake). Furthermore, Signet-ring
supports the lifecycle management of source identities (using cryptographic keys) and relationships
between objects and sources. This lifecycle management includes the revocation of source identity
keys and previously accepted object-source relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
