<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics | Mahesh Arumugam</title>
    <link>/tag/statistics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Statistics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Statistics</title>
      <link>/tag/statistics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Your Flights be Delayed?</title>
      <link>/project/scale-mids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/scale-mids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air travel has a significant role in shaping economies of states and this it is important to optimize every
aspect of the flight cycle to increase the quality of airline&amp;rsquo;s services, especially, the consistent on-time
departure of flights. However, due to multiple factors, airline flight delay is inevitable, and thus have to be
accounted for by the airline company executives in order to optimize value to multiple stakeholders &amp;ndash;from the
shareholders to the customers.  In this project, we seek to address the following question: can weather and
airline data collected two hours before the scheduled departure time, predict whether the flight will be
delayed 15 minutes or more? The models we developed in this project, predict the delay with an accuracy of $82%$.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What made the Pacific Northwest move during the July 4th weekend?</title>
      <link>/project/stats-mids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/stats-mids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The effects of the COVID-19 pandemic have been felt and are still being felt around the world. In particular,
the tourism industry suffered extreme economic losses between the many travel restrictions, cessation of
communal social activities, and widespread fear of contracting the virus. Specifically, in 2020, there was a
$35%$ reduction in domestic travel, resulting significant revenue loss. By contrast, there was an uptick in
domestic travel in 2021. In this project, we seek to understand how vaccination rates are impacting vacation
mobility in the Pacific Northwest during summer 2021. We explore the relationship between number of trips between
100 and 500 miles and COVID-19 vaccinations controlled for key related attributes, including population
density and number of COVID-19 cases. In addition, we also consider several additional factors that influence
travel, such as employment status, state restrictions, and political ideology. We also note that this study only
focuses on a small time period -July 4th weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
